# Casey Smith

# **Enterprise Data Analyst**

Nashville, Tennessee ∇ Phone: (865)850-9436

ΔEmail: crs4f1988@gmail.com \(\nabla\)Github: https://github.com/crs4f1988

#### **About Me**

An accomplished leader in supporting a wide variety of customers through practical-problem solving and data-driven methods in an array of fields. Focused on telling the story of processes and solutions as illustrated through qualitative and quantitative data with an empathetic and connection-based mindset. Experienced in both team and individual style working environments, and using adaptive decision-making in a rapidly evolving sector.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN - Data Analyst Apprentice

July 2022 - Present

Intensive full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

**Syndigo, (Remote Job),** Chicago, IL - Enterprise Data Analyst, Tier 2 Technical Support Analyst, Customer Success Manager, Tier 1 Support Analyst

February 2021 - Present

- Used Microsoft Excel and extensions to analyze supplier to recipient data, finding validation errors and discerning problem attributes
- Utilized several backend tools (Go.Diagnostic and FSE migration tool) to reprocess data, make backend item deletes, set account stagings, and pause publications.
- Implemented many new recipient accounts using outstanding processes as an assistant to our director of GDSN, Hugh McBride
- Created and managed tickets using Atlas JIRA for tracking

 Facilitated numerous training and product demonstrations for customers in a support capacity.

# **Parman Energy Group**, Nashville, TN — Customer Relationship Coordinator

September 2017 - January 2019

- Acted as office coordinator and ordered supplies, processed mail, and helped maintain break room
- Processed Online orders and handled the addition of products added to website
- Managed company CRM software and trained employees on data entry and process

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Nashville Software School**

**Data Analytics Certification** 

Expected Grad Date: Jan 2023

## Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN

Bachelors of Arts in Global Studies - Minor in Spanish

Bachelors of Science in Journalism

Aug 2007 - May 2011

#### **SKILLS**

- Data Analysis
- SQL
- Excel
- Git/GitHub
- Salesforce
- Atlas JIRA
- Customer-Service
- Fluent English and Conversational Spanish
- Project Management

### **Data Projects**

**Nashville City Cemetery** - Created marketing material to drive business toa historic cemetery, using advanced Microsoft Excel techniques to analyze and interpret burial data.

**TN Prescriber's Project** - Used SQL to analyze and interpret prescription data from healthcare providers in the state of TN. Used intermediate techniques to join, alias and aggregate data.